# Muhammad Hassan

# **Software Engineer** (iOS)

#### **Muhammad Hassan**

Lahore, Pakistan

+92 333 453 0486

hassankhll@hotmail.com

https://github.com/HassanSE

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hassanse

# **Summary**

Seasoned iOS Engineer with 8+ years of experience in crafting and publishing apps. I am skilled in writing tests, refactoring, moduling, and writing overall cleaner code.

With proven experience of software engineering principles and practices, I deliver promising work that helps businesses grow. With an ever learning attitude, I am looking forward to being a software architect.

#### **Skills**

Code	Design
Swift, Objective-C, Python	SwiftUI, UIKit, Animations
Patterns	CI/CD
MVVM, MVI, MVC	Bitrise, Travis CI, Fastlane
Frameworks	Concurrency
Frameworks Combine, RxSwift, Core Data	Concurrency Structured Concurrency, GCD
	·

## **Experience**

# PayPay Corporation / iOS Engineer

June 2021 - Present, Tokyo, Japan

PayPay is the largest mobile payment app with over 50 million registered users in Japan. Being a part of the consumer app team, I work on new features, refactoring, fixing bugs and taking care of legacy code. The goal is to provide our users a safe and reliable platform to perform digital payments.

https://apps.apple.com/app/id1435783608

## Digitify Ltd / iOS Engineer

December 2017 - May 2021, Lahore, Pakistan

At Digitify, I've got the chance to work on Fintech and RegTech domains. With my team, I've built a branchless banking product from ground up and shaping it into the leading banking application in UAE.

https://apps.apple.com/in/app/id1498302242

# Intagleo Systems / Software Engineer

September 2014 - May 2017, Lahore, Pakistan

Starting out as a Windows developer, I worked and shipped over 10 successful digital signage solutions for their potential U.S based client. That led to another 3 years contract with the company. In addition, I wrote 2 in-house iOS apps before I left in 2017.

## **Education**

# Govt. College University / BS Computer Science

September 2010 - August 2014, Lahore, Pakistan

• CGPA of 3.17

# Govt. Islamia College Civil Lines / ICS

September 2008 - July 2010, Lahore, Pakistan

• A Grade